Finding Aid for the Ho Young Ham Papers LSC.0697
UCLA Library Special Collections
Ho Young Ham papers
1873-1984
UCLA Library Special Collections
Ham, Ho Young
LSC.0697
41 boxes
4 cartons
4 oversize boxes
Ho Young Ham was born in Seoul, Korea on May 5, 1868 and immigrated to Hawaii in 1905 with his wife, Hannah Chur Ham (1882-1979). The Ho Young Ham papers consist of artifacts, audio recordings, books, clothing, correspondence, manuscripts, photographs, and printed material that document Mr. Ham and his family, his professional life as a sugar plantation employee and Korean Methodist Church minister, and his involvement in Korean nationalist activities.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Juliette and Norman Breazeal, 2005.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9953727273606533
Biography
Ho Young Ham was born in Seoul, Korea on May 5, 1868 and immigrated to Hawaii in 1905 with his wife, Hannah Chur Ham (1882-1979). Upon arriving in the Territory of Hawaii he began work for the Hawaiian Commercial and Sugar Company; he retired in 1949 after 44 years of service. Mr. Ham was active in the Korean National Association and the Korean Benevolent Society, but a major focus of his life was his role as a lay minister for the Korean Methodist Church in Sprecklesville, Maui, territory of Hawaii. The Ham family included ten children. Ham daughters included: Suney Ham Ow, Clara Ham Cabrinha, Mary Ham Hyum, Salome Ham Ambrose, Dora Ham Kim, and Elizabeth Ham Rosen. The Ham's four sons included: Norman Ham (1910-1950), John Ham, Paul Ham, and Simon Ham. Other prominent family members included Mr. Tai Young Hahm (1872-1964), vice president of the Republic of Korea under president Syngman Rhee (1875-1965), and first cousin to Mr. Ho Young Ham, and Mr. Pyong-choon Hahm (1932-1983), son of Tai Young Hahm, an influential legal scholar, Korean ambassador to the United States, and former national security adviser to the President of the Republic of Korea. Mr. Ham died in March 1954 in Maui.
Scope and Content
This collection documents the activities of Ho Young Ham, a Korean immigrant to Maui, Hawaii in 1905. The materials reflect Mr. Ham's role as husband, father, sugar plantation employee, Methodist minister, and Korean nationalist activist. The bulk of the collection consists of Mr. Ham's monographs, including a number of theological books. The collection also includes artifacts, clothing (including some Korean traditional dress), correspondence, ledgers, manuscripts (including Mr. Ham's diaries), photographs, and printed materials that reflect Mr. Ham's varied interests and pursuits. Some materials are in Korean and Chinese
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Artifacts, ca. 1915-1941 (2 boxes and 1 oversize box).
Audio recordings, 1961 (1 box).
Books, 1873-1994 (29 boxes), subseries A-F as follows:
Education.
History.
Literature.
Miscellaneous.
Theology.
Yearbooks.
Clothing, ca. 1900-1975 (4 cartons).
Correspondence, 1906-1984 (1.5 boxes).
Ledgers, ca. 1919-1943 (1.5 boxes).
Manuscripts, 1905-1984 (3.5 boxes).
Photographs, ca. 1900-1953 (1 box).
Printed materials, ca. 1905-1982 (1 box), subseries A-C as follows:
Ephemera.
Maps.
Records and certificates.
Costume.; Korean American Methodists -- Hawaii -- Archives.; Sugar workers -- Hawaii -- Archives.; Ham, Ho Young, 1868-1954--Archives.
- Series 1: Artifacts, ca. 1895-1941; 2 boxes and 1 oversize box.
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains two Korean flags sewn by Hannah Ham, ca. 1910, and miscellaneous other items including a cane cutter knife, a handmade Korean wind chime, small metal objects, and a variety of rubber stamps.
  - Embroidered oblong bag., ca. 1910.; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Korean flag made by Hannah Ham., ca. 1910.; 5' x 4'. (Box 48)
  - Korean flag made by Hannah Ham., ca. 1910.; 3' x 3'. (Box 49)
  - Ladle., no date.; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    General note
    Made in Germany.
  - Wind chime with Korean coins, embroidered charms, and ribbon., no date.; 3 items. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Bookmarks, cord, and decorative tassel., ca. 1895, ca. 1908, 1941.; 5 items. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Fabric bookmarks in purple and white with embroidered image of Korean flag. White braid cord possibly a civil servant's belt given to Ho Young Ham for assisting Queen Min [Myongsong Hwanghu] before her assassination (ca. 1895). Knot work on the sool is known as madeup (??), often translated as Korean knots.
  - Cane cutter hand knife., undated.; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Porcelain ink pads., undated.; Lid already broken in three pieces at time of appraisal and accessioning (ca. 2005). (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Metal artifacts., ca. 1900.; 3 items. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Ear cleaner, wedding gift from Ho Young Ham to Hannah Ham [?]. Metal coin purse. Unidentified metal object.
  - Stamps., undated.; 10 items. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Miscellaneous woodblock stamps, and one circular metal stamp. Two rubber stamps from the Korean National Association. One rubber stamp from the Korean Red Cross.
- Series 2: Audio recordings, 1961; 1 box.
  This series contains audio reels and cassette tapes of Hannah Ham being interviewed by her son, Simon, regarding family history and emigration to Hawaii. The series also includes a hardcopy transcript of the interview.
  - Hannah Ham's memoir., 1961.; 5" audio reel. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Recorded in Korean. Mrs. Ham is interviewed by her son, Paul. She relates family history and her emigration to Hawaii.
  - Hannah Ham's memoir., 1961.; 7" audio reel. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Hannah Ham's memoir., 1961.; Cassettes. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Transcription of Hannah Ham's memoir tapes., 1961.; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    English transcription of tapes made by Paul Ham of his mother, Hannah, as she related family history and her emigration to Hawaii. Translation by Henry Ahn of Brea, California in Honolulu.
- Series 3: Books, 1873-1994; 29 boxes.
  This series contains books on a variety of topics (but mostly theological in nature), in a combination of languages that include Korean, Chinese, and English.
  Arranged in the following subseries:
  3A. Education
  3B. History
  3C. Literature
  3D. Miscellaneous
  3E. Theology
  3F. Yearbooks.
  - Subseries 3A: Education, 1901-1931
    - (Pot'ong hakkyo haktoyong) Chosono tokpon = Elementary school Korean language book, volume 7., ca. 1911.; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 4)
      Chinese and Korean text. Illustrated. Author: Choson Ch'ongdokpu = Japanese Government in Korea. Publisher: (Choson Sojok Inswae Chuseik Hoesa), Seoul = Japanese government in Seoul, Korea.
    - (Sinch'an) Ch'oktok wanp'yon = Complete letter writing., 1912.; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 5)
      Chinese and Korean text. Author: U-gyun Kim. Publisher: Chungang Sogwan, Seoul.
    - (Sinsik Onmun) Kadyong kandok = Style of writing to be used in family correspondence., 1913.; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 6)
      Chinese and Korean text. Editor: Ik-hyong No. Publisher: Pangmun Sogwan, Seoul = Pangmun Bookstore.
    - [Math textbook?]., ca. 1910.; 8.5" x 6". (Box 4, Folder 7)
      Includes math problems and tables in Arabic numbers.
    - An address to mothers on the care of children., 1911.; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 8)
      Korean and English text. By Mrs. Noble. Publisher: the Korean Religious Tract Society, The Tract House, Seoul.
    - Ch'odung Kugo ojon = Elementary national language dictionary., 1909.; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 9)
      Chinese and Korean text. Author: Hui-yang Kim. Publisher: Yuil Sogwan, Seoul = Yuil bookstore.
    - Ch'okah Ch'yopkoyng = Beginning learning short cuts to a faster way., 1912.; 5 items. (Box 5, Folder 1)
      Author: Han Sung-gon. Publisher: Kwangmyong Sogwan, P'yongyang.
    - Chosono tokpon = Elementary Korean language book, volume I., 1930.; 1 item. (Box 5, Folder 2)
      Author/Publisher: Japanese Regional Government, Seoul.
    - Elementary geography, Hulbert's educational series, no. 1, 2nd ed., 1907.; 1 item. (Box 5, Folder 3)
      Title page in English. Korean text. Author: Mrs. E. H. Miller. Published: Korean Tract Society.
    - Geographical gazetteer of the world, Hulbert series, no. II, 3rd ed., 1909.; 3 items. (Box 5, Folder 4)
      Color maps. One copy inscribed Ham Ho Young.
    - Hanchong Choson = Chinese, Japanese and Korean written detailed explanation., undated.; 1 item. (Box 5, Folder 5)
      Authors: Gung-jun Nam and Shen Song [?]. Publisher: Tongyang Sowon.
    - Hygiene of parturition., 1908.; 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 1)
      Female care before and after childbirth. Publisher: Korean Religious Tract Society.
    - Jitchi renshu shinyobun gosendai = Newest useful five thousand subject areas., 1901.; 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 2)
      Author/reviser: Inane Haskin. Published: Osaka City.
    - Korean reader number 1, 3rd ed., 1909.; 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 3)
      Chinese, English, and Korean text. Author: Rev. J.S. Gale D.D. Publisher: Korean Religious Tract Society, Hulbert Educational Series. No. 3.
    - Korean work on astrology., undated.; 2 items. (Box 6, Folder 4)
      No publication data.
    - Lecture on behavior., 1907.; 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 5)
      Korean text. Front and back cover missing. Arabic numeral page numbers.
    - Newly selected Chinese textbook, volume I., undated.; 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 6)
      Text is Chinese. Illustrated. Publisher: Chinese Printing Company, Shanghai.
    - Nihon sheik ken 1 and ken 2 = Japanese history book, volume I and II., 1907.; 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Nihongo dokuhon jinjokayo kan 1 = Japanese language reading book high school, 1st ed., 1920.; 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 8)
      Inside cover inscribed "Shinayo Sugawara. Camp Two. Japanese school." Published: Tokyo.
    - Nihongo dokuhon jinjokayo kan 5 = Japanese language reading book for elementary school, 5th ed., 1922.; 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 9)
      Published: Tokyo.
    - Nitsu Shin Kaiwa Neumon = Japanese Chinese conversation, introductory class., 1905.; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 1)
      Illustrations include Japanese cigarette boxes: Lily Cigarettes, Cherry Cigarettes, Star Cigarettes, and Longlife Cigarettes.
    - Palmer method of business writing., 1925.; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 2)
      Author: A.N. Palmer. Publisher: A.N. Palmer Company.
    - Segye chi wiin = World biography of famous people., 1929.; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 3)
      Chinese and Korean text. Illustrated. Author: To-yong Chong and Yong-jin Kim. Publisher: Pando Ch'ulp'ansa, Seoul = Peninsula Publishing Company, Seoul.
    - Shogaki naikokushi hoshu = Elementary school domestic language book., 1901.; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Author: Shinpo Banji = Ho-ban Tsugime. Publisher: Kinkodo Shoseki kabushi kaisa, Tokyo = Kin ho dou printing joint stocks company, Tokyo.
    - Shuyoron = Study of nutrition., 1909.; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 5)
      Author: Kato Kumaichiro. Publisher: Toado Shobo, Tokyo.
    - Sin sidae ui soganjip = New modern letter writing textbook., 1931.; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 6)
      Chinese and Korean text. Editor: Ui-yong Kang. Publisher: Hanhung Sorim, Seoul; also given Yongch'ang Sogwan, Seoul = Hanhung Bookstore.
    - Sinch'an Ch'odung sohak = Learning Korean., 1909.; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 7)
      Chinese and Korean text. Author: Sang-ik Yi.
    - Sinch'an Ch'odung sohak, Volume III and IV = New version of 4th elementary text., 1908.; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 8)
      Primer for elementary school. Cover page and publishing information in Chinese. Main text is Chinese and Korean. Author: Sang-ik Yi. Published: Seoul.
    - Sinch'an Ch'odung sohak, Volume IV = Learning Korean, volume IV., 1909.; 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Sinjong Ch'onjamun = New edition of one thousand characters., 1914.; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 1)
      Chinese and Korean text. Author: Choong-jong Yi. Publisher: Kwangdong Soguk, Seoul = Kung-Tong Bookstore, Seoul.
    - Sinjong sansul = Arithmetic book., 1909.; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 2)
      Text Chinese and Korean. Editor: Chae-gon Yang. Publisher: Yui Sogwan, Seoul. Issuing Company: Yui Bookstore, Seoul.
    - Taehan chiji chon = New advanced Korean geography., 1909.; 2 items. (Box 8, Folder 3)
      Chinese and Korean text. Illustrated. Author: In-ho Chong. Publisher: Posongsa, Seoul.
    - Ungbyon Pop = How to speak., 1911.; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 4)
      Author: Sin Hung-u (minister and graduate of USC).
    - What a young boy ought to know., 1907.; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 5)
      Korean and English text. By Rev. Sylvanus Stall, D.D. "Translated from the English by a mother of sons for the sons of other mothers." Publisher: The Korean Religious Tract Society.
    - World of students., 1920 July 3.; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 6)
      Chinese and Korean text. Editor: P'ar-yong Ch'oe. Publisher: Hansong Toso chusik hoesa ch'ulp'anbu, Seoul.
  - Subseries 3B: History, 1900-1994
    - Amerik'a Hyongmyong = American revolution, volume I., 1915.; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 7)
      Chinese and Korean text. Illustrated (picture of George Washington). Publisher: Kungminbosa, Honolulu = Korean National Herald, Honolulu.
    - Chodung Ponguk Yaksa = Beginners Korean history., 1908.; 2 items. (Box 8, Folder 8)
      Chinese and Korean text. Illustrated. One copy inscribed: "Suney Ham, Korean School, Sprecklesville, Maui J.H." Editor: Yon-ho Chong. Publisher: Kyodong Umungwan, Seoul, Korea. Publisher: Yu-Hu Bookstore.
    - Chodung Ponguk Yaksa = Beginners simplified Korean history., 1908.; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 9)
      Title and publishing information in Chinese. Text is Chinese and Korean. Last paged inscribed with name "Hyun Chang Hoon." Comments on front cover: "private school history book" and "examined by Education Department."
    - Ch'ong-Il Chongi = Sino Japanese war., 1900.; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 1)
      Korean text. Author: Syngman Rhee = Sung-man Yi). Publisher: T'aep'yongyang Chapohisa, Honolulu, Hawaii.
    - Chosom Yoksa = Korean history., 1931.; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 2)
      Chinese and Korean text. Author: Nam-Son Ch'oe. Publisher: Tongmyong Sa, Seoul.
    - Ham T'ae-yong Ong segye tlchugu = World travel of Hahm Tae Young., 1957.; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 3)
      Chinese and Korean text. Author: Chong-jun Kim. Publisher: Songmun, haksa, Seoul. Back of book inscribed to Hannah Hahm and Clara Cabrinha from "Uncle Tai Young Ham."
    - Han'guk Kyongjesa = Economic history of Korea., 1920.; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 4)
      Chinese, Korean, and English text. Author: Earl K. Paik. Publisher: Sinhan Minbosa, Los Angeles, California.
    - Han'guk Tongnip undongsa = Korean independence movement history, volume I., 1921.; 3 items. (Box 9, Folder 5)
      Chinese and Korean text. Author: Kim Pyong-jo. Publisher: Uionsa, Shanghai. Publisher: Shun-Yang Society, Shanghai.
    - Han-guk tongsa = Korean history., 1917.; 2 items. (Box 10, Folder 1)
      Chinese, English, and Korean text. Includes pictures of the Korean royal family. Author: Lai-hang Kwak. Publisher: The Industrial Grocery, Honolulu, Hawaii.
    - Hawaiian-Japanese annual., 1922.; 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 2)
      Japanese text. Island directory. Publisher: The Hawaii Shinpo Sha, Ltd., Honolulu, T.H.
    - History of Korea., 1915.; 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 3)
      Author: Lee Sang Jee. Illustrated.
    - Kungmin Pobyong sol = All people must be soldiers., 1911.; 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 4)
      Author: Pak Yong-man. Illustrated. Publisher: Sinhan Minbosa, San Francisco = New Korean Press.
    - Pamphlet--The Korean independence movement., 1919.; 1 item. (Box 11, Folder 1)
      Text in English. From front cover: "Actual photographs showing peaceful demonstrations of the Koreans for independence and brutal treatment accorded them by Japanese soldiery." Publisher: The Oriental Press, Shanghai.
    - Portuguese-Hawaiian memories. Manuel Cabrinha's death date given on fly leaf as July 31, 1970., 1930.; 1 item. (Box 11, Folder 2)
      Author: J.F. Freitas. Inscription from Manuel Mediros Cabrinha to his daughter, Clara.
    - Syosa Kon'gukchi = Switzerland history., 1907.; 1 item. (Box 11, Folder 3)
      Korean text. Translator: Pyong-hyon. Publisher: Taehan hwangsyong Pangmun Syogwan.
    - Taehan tongnip undongbi Yongum Chaejyong podan., 1919.; 1 item. (Box 11, Folder 4)
      Korean text. Book contains all the names of the Koreans in the Hawaiian Islands who contributed to the Korean independence movement, including the amount they donated. Publisher: Kungminhoe, Honolulu; Publisher: Korean National Association, Honolulu.
    - Tehan tongnip hyolchongi = Korean independence movement., 1919.; 3 items. (Box 11, Folder 5)
      Korean text. Illustrated. Author: Kim Yong-u, Kim Y.W. Publisher: T'aep'yongyang Chapchisa, Honolulu = Honolulu Pacific Magazine Company.
    - The fact of economical conditions in Korea., 1937.; 1 item. (Box 11, Folder 6)
      Preface in English (includes statistics). Text in Korean. Author: Hahn Tcheng.
    - The spirit of independence, 2nd ed., 1917.; 2 items. (Box 11, Folder 7)
      Preface in English. Preface by Rev. Y.M. Moon, president of the Korean Press Association, includes short biographical history of Syngman Rhee
    - Their footsteps: a pictorial history of Koreans in Hawaii since 1903., 1994.; 1 item. (Box 12, Folder 1)
      Editor: Dr. Samuel S. O. Lee. Publication jointly funded by grants from the State of Hawaii and the Korea Foundation. Page 193 includes photo of Ho Young Ham and Hannah Ham, poem by Mr. Ham, and reproduction of Mr. Ham's "exhorter's license."
    - Tongnip Cho'ngsin = The spirit of independence., 1910.; 1 item. (Box 12, Folder 2)
      Inside cover is inscribed "Mr. Ham Ho Young." Two 1917 versions are also in the collection.
  - Subseries 3C: Literature, 1900-1930
    - Choson munhak kolchakchip = Korean literature collection., 1925.; 1 item. (Box 12, Folder 3)
      Chinese and Korean text. Author: To-bin Chang. Publisher: Yongch'ang Sogwan, Seoul.
    - Choson tonghwa taejip = Korean children's folk stories., ca. 1926.; 1 item. (Box 12, Folder 4)
      Chinese and Korean text. Author: ui-rin Sim. Publisher: Hongsong Toso Chusik Hoesa, Seoul = Seoul Bookstore Association.
    - Cripple Tom, 2nd ed., 1900.; 1 item. (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Kwi ui Song = Ghost boys, volume II., undated.; 1 item. (Box 12, Folder 6)
      Chinese and Korean text. Author: Kukch'o = In-jik Yi. Publisher: Chungag Sogwan, Seoul = Central Bookstore, Seoul.
    - Pilgrim's progress, part I and II., 1920.; 1 item. (Box 12, Folder 7)
      Translated by Mrs. H.G. Underwood, M.D. Publisher: The Christian Literature Society of Korea.
    - Sigajip = Collection of poems., 1930.; 1 item. (Box 12, Folder 8)
      Chinese text. Illustrated. Poetry of Kwang-su Yi, Tong-huan, and Ik-hwan Chu. Publisher: Yongch'ang Sogwan, Seoul = Yong Ch'ang Book House (a school), Seoul.
    - Usun sori = Funny stories., 1910.; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 1)
      Chinese and Korean text. Author: Ch'i-ho Yun. Publisher: Sin han'gukpo sa, Honolulu, Hawaii.
  - Subseries 3D: Miscellaneous, 1905-1934
    - [Child's school book?]., ca. 1910.; 9" x 6". (Box 13, Folder 2)
      Korean text. Illustrated, including color.
    - [Unidentified]., 1915.; 9" x 6". (Box 13, Folder 3)
      Published in Tokyo.
    - [Unidentified]., ca. 1910.; 8.5" x 6". (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - [Unidentified]., ca. 1910.; 7.5" x 5". (Box 13, Folder 5)
      Notations in pencil.
    - [Unidentified]., ca. 1910.; 4.5" x 3.5". (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - [Unidentified]., ca. 1910.; 7.5" x 5". (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - [Unidentified]., ca. 1910.; 9" x 6". Illustrated. (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Ai tongmu = Children's friends magazines., 1934 February, October, November.; 3 items. (Box 13, Folder 9)
      Publisher: Ai tongmusa, P'yongyang = American Missionary, Seoul.
    - Chibang Haengjong non chon = Description of local administration (rules for government entity)., 1908.; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 10)
      Text Chinese and Korean. Collection by: Song-gu Cho. Publisher: Chungang Sogwan, Seoul = Center Bookstore, Seoul.
    - Ch'omok P'ilchi., 1909.; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 11)
      Chinese and Korean text. Author: Yun-su Chong. Publisher: Kwangdok Sogwan, Seoul.
    - Chuhae hyonhaeng minhyong sosong sosik = Civil and criminal law suit forms., 1909.; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 12)
      Chinese and Korean text. Author: Hong-jong Yi. Publisher: Yungmun'gwan, Seoul.
    - Chungsong Piyu yoji., 1906.; 1 item. (Box 14, Folder 1)
      Text Korean. Author: (Dunkin): translated by Joon Yuen Ahn.
    - Kaebyok., 1920.; 1 item. (Box 14, Folder 2)
      Editor: Ton-hwa Yi. Publisher: Kaebyok, Seoul = Kai-bei Society.
    - Kaejong hyongpop taejon., 1908.; 1 item. (Box 14, Folder 3)
      Chinese text. Publisher: Uijinsa, Seoul.
    - Kokugo Kanbun Shinjiten., 1905.; 1 item. (Box 14, Folder 4)
      Author: Inoue Yorikuni. Publisher: Okura Shoten, Tokyo City.
    - Korean Red Cross Society photo pamphlet., 1919 July 1.; 1 item. (Box 14, Folder 5)
      Contains statement regarding the reconstituted Korean Red Cross Society.
    - Kotaishi Denka gogaiuki = Crown prince majesty foreign travel record., 1924.; 1 item. (Box 14, Folder 6)
      Travelogue of Prince Hiro Hito. Authors: Sawada Setsuzo (official of Foreign Affairs) and Count Futara Yoshinori of the Imperial Household. Publishers: Ni Ti Niti Newspaper Company, Tokyo and Mai Niti Newspaper Company, Osaka.
    - Kyoyuk wolbo = Monthly announcements volumes I and II., 1908.; 1 item. (Box 14, Folder 7)
      Korean text. Editor: Ok Namgung. Publisher: Kyoyuk wolbosa, Hansyong, Seoul.
    - Paedal kongnon = Opinion of Korean people; collection of articles., 1924.; 1 item. (Box 15, Folder 1)
      Editor: Kwang-guk Pin. Publisher: Sanghae Umu Sinsang, Shanghai.
    - PiPa music., undated.; 1 item. (Box 15, Folder 2)
      Cover illustrated in color (woman seated in a rickshaw). Pages numbered in modern (Arabic) numerals.
    - Sa Sii namjonggi., 1913.; 1 item. (Box 15, Folder 3)
      Chinese and Korean text. Author: Man-jung Kim. Publisher: Yongp'ung Sogwan, Seoul = Yun-fon Bookstore.
    - Sin yoja = New woman., 1920 March, April, May.; 3 items. (Box 15, Folder 4)
      Title and publishing information in Chinese. Main text in Chinese and Korean. Editor: Ppillingssu Puin. Publisher: Sin Yojasa, Seoul = New Woman Society, Seoul.
    - Songbook in Korean with illustrations and vignettes., 1928 September 3.; 1 item. (Box 15, Folder 5)
      Mimeographed, bound copy; not professionally published. Includes Korean compositions in addition to European standards. Attributed to Reedley Korean Mission of the M.E. Church, South.
    - Standard of moral conduct and social ethics., undated.; 1 item. (Box 15, Folder 6)
      Text in English, Hawaiian, Portuguese, Filipino-Tagalog, Filipino-Ilocano, Korean, Japanese, Chinese. Published in Honolulu, Hawaii.
    - Suhak ui no = Economically disadvantaged self-improvement., 1921.; 1 item. (Box 15, Folder 7)
      Text Chinese and Korean. Author: Hyon Ch'oe. Publisher: Kohaksaeng Kaldophoe, Seoul.
    - Taisho ninben toyo nikki., 1912.; 1 item. (Box 15, Folder 8)
      Japanese travel guide. Publisher: Hakubunkan, Tokyo, Japan.
    - Tanbang sinp'yon = Herb prescription catalog, newly edited., 1909.; 1 item. (Box 15, Folder 9)
      Chinese and Korean text. Author: Yag-yong Chong. Publisher: Umun'gwan, Kyongsong Kyo-dong (Seoul).
    - The cross word puzzle book., 1909.; 1 item. (Box 16, Folder 1)
      Cover and some inside text in English. Author: Chen She Yong. Published: Printing person Yu Zsu She, Shanghai.
    - Tugyonsong = Song of bird, volume I and II., 1912.; 1 item. (Box 16, Folder 2)
      Chinese and Korean text. Illustrated. Author: U-il Son. Publisher: Pogup Sogwan, Seoul.